Kyle Feffer

GIS Analyst

6530 Double Eagle Dr, #708, Woodridge, IL, 60517 Phone: 818.923.2263 E-Mail: feffer.kyle@gmail.com

Summary of Qualifications

Skilled GIS professional using geospatial analysis and programming concepts to develop complex, multidisciplined solutions within the renewable energy industry. Earned a Bachelor's of Science in Geography and a minor in Geographic Information Science. Experience in multiple public sector internships before becoming a leading member in an professional engineering environment. After my work in the energy field, I transitioned back into the public sector working for a Department of Energy National Laboratory at Argonne. Furthermore, I am currently working toward obtaining a Master's degree in GIS.

Technical Skills

GIS and Data Analysis

- Outstanding with a variety of geospatial software including both ESRI and opensource QGIS
- Demonstrated history of creating and refining geospatial models, processes, and scripts
- Exceptional web mapping skills including the creation of web mapping applications

Computer Science

- Proficient with Python, Java, and JavaScript as well as the ArcGIS API for both Python and JavaScript
- Experienced with JSON and GeoJSON data formats as well as accessing third party APIs in these formats
- Active team member of several new GIS and web development projects within my current organization

Education

University of Minnesota-Twin Cities, Minneapolis, MN Geography B.S.

Class of May 2018

Geographic Information Science Minor

4 Year Presidential Scholarship Recipient

University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI

Class of May 2021

Cartography and Geographic Information Systems M.S. - GIS Development

Online Master's Program in GIS and Web Map Programming

Relevant Professional Experience

GIS Analyst March 2020 to Present

Argonne National Laboratory – Decision and Infrastructure Sciences Division (DIS) – Lemont, IL

Served as a geospatial analyst working directly with sponsors on large scale utility analysis projects. Types of projects include natural disaster simulation and response planning, pandemic response, and federal facility safety plans. Most notably provided work on FEMA's Resilience Analysis and Planning Tool (RAPT) as well as data collection for IEMA and the Army Corps of Engineers in response to COVID-19.

GIS Specialist

June 2018 to February 2020

Westwood Professional Services - Power Generation Department - Minnetonka, MN

Worked in a fast paced, professional environment leading the development of wind and solar farms. Performed several essential spatial analysis functions including wetland management, maintaining spatial databases for infrastructure, slope analysis, and served as a lead curator of web based GIS applications to support field staff in the collection and monitoring of construction data. Deeply enhanced my knowledge of ESRI products including the functionality of ArcGIS online as well as learned new software platforms including GlobalMapper, Civil 3D, and AutoCAD. Improved my cartographic abilities while learning aspects about in depth GIS model development. Modified and wrote new procedures and standards for several for spatial tasks across the company. Experienced a high intensity work environment with tight deadlines and strict requirements.

Geographic Information Systems and Summer Field Intern

May 2017 to August 2017

The City of Edina - Engineering Department - Edina, MN

Poured through city records to create databases of information related to traffic management, transit programs, street reconstruction, water resources management, and storm hydrology. Additionally, took field GPS/GNSS measurements of various city infrastructure and natural resources as well as collected data for traffic studies.

Geographic Information Systems Intern Hennepin County - GIS Department - Minneapolis, MN

June 2016 to May 2017

Worked with and learned from highly experienced GIS professionals doing projects for Hennepin County departments such as the Department of Emergency Management, Public Works, and the County Attorney's Office. Projects included data management, map creation, putting together public facing applications, and more. Major projects included planning a county wide, quarterly GIS departmental meeting and working on enterprise level projects such as creating a database of historic aerial imagery by georeferencing images from 1940 to 2015.